And, you know, I think, unfortunately, the very smart, I think, bet that we made on Holocaust
education to serve as anti-Semitism education, in this new media environment, I think that is
beginning to break down a little bit. Because, you know, Holocaust education is absolutely essential.
But I think it may be confusing some of our young people about anti-Semitism,
because they learn about big, strong Nazis hurting weak, emaciated Jews. And they think,
oh, anti-Semitism is like anti-black racism, right? Powerful white people against powerless black
people. So when on TikTok, all day long, they see powerful Israelis hurting weak, skinny Palestinians,
it's not surprising that they think, oh, I know, the lesson of the Holocaust is you fight Israel.
You fight the big, powerful people hurting the weak people. That's not how the Holocaust happened,
right? We all know that. We know that it happened because the Germans insisted that the Jews,
one percent of the population, were responsible for all their problems, just like people insist
that Israel, the size of New Jersey, is responsible for all the world's problems today.
So in that viral clip of Sarah Hurwitz trying to callously discredit young Jewish people's
changing stances towards Israel, she reveals herself to not only be inhumane, but also ignorant
of how oppression works, specifically the oppression of black people, which she decided to bring up
to illustrate her point. So basically, she tried to differentiate between anti-black racism
and anti-semitism by saying that anti-black racism exists because black people are, or
at least are seen, as a powerless minority, whereas anti-semitism exists because Jewish people
are seen as a dangerously powerful minority. Her implication is that black people are solely
stereotyped as backward, primitive, and ripe for exploitation, whereas Jewish people, by contrast,
are stereotyped as shrewd, scheming, and an existential threat. And from this, she argues,
people just can't truly understand why Israel must kill so many Gazans because no one else
knows what it's like to face oppression because of being scapegoated in such a way.
Once again, as she puts it, in a way that makes a minority community be seen as having too much
power, not too little. But this is a completely ahistorical and false differentiation, and it reveals
why her larger conclusion is so flawed. These two forms of oppression work much more similarly
than she seems to realize. Black people and other minority groups have repeatedly faced scapegoating
because they were seen as too powerful and as posing an organized, political, and intellectual
threat to white society, even though this is a dynamic that Hurwitz seems to only attribute to
anti-semitism. And I'll go through just a few examples, but first, during the Reconstruction era,
white supremacist politicians warned of the threat of Negro rule. They spread conspiracies that newly
enfranchised black voters were plotting to overthrow white civilization. Massacres like that at Wilmington
and other political violence were justified by portraying black people as cunning and dangerously
powerful. During the Civil Rights era, the FBI monitored and sought to dispose of civil rights leaders
like Malcolm X and MLK precisely because they were seen as intelligent, articulate leaders who could
move crowds as units and who pose a significant threat to the existing power structure. And even
contemporarily, these attacks on the woke mind virus and on black academics often frame them as evil
masterminds who have schemed to rewrite history, and who have successfully indoctrinated the country's
youth to push America towards cultural collapse. This rhetoric scapegoats an entire array of societal and
economic issues on this infinitely small minority of black professors in elite education because
portrays them as having way more power than they actually do. And I'm not saying that anti-semitism and
anti-blackness are the exact same or have the exact same history, but what she brings up as an exceptional
aspect of anti-semitism that is a minority group being scapegoated for having too much power, too much
impact, is actual reality of many forms of identity-based persecution. And because that premise is incorrect,
her subsequent claim that young people are confusing the takeaways of the Holocaust does not have a
valid foundation. That's because even if we take into account all of the complex ways in which
scapegoating can be carried out, no country should ever be permitted to carry out genocide against
anyone. And if you're seeing mass amounts of carnage, it's okay to protest it. But very importantly,
this isn't just a takeaway that you get from observing the Jewish victims of the Holocaust,
but also the Roma, Jehovah's Witnesses, people with disabilities, queer people, and yes,
even black people, people with multiple of those identities, etc. They were also victims of the
Holocaust and other atrocities for whom the same takeaway applies. But what do you think? Would
you want me to write a Substack article to go deeper? Let me know in the comments and of course,
follow for more.